

Simon Hoang 07928 669 888 simon.hoang23@gmail.com Manchester & London

United Kingdom

Portfolio
Behance
Dribbble
Instagram
LinkedIn

www.simonhoang.com
www.behance.net/simonhoang
www.dribbble.com/simonhoang23
www.instagram.com/uxdon
www.linkedin.com/in/simonhoang23

ABOUT

My role as a UXer centres around putting users at the core of product design, focusing on user experience as well as improving design practices and consistency. I concentrate on creating an appealing product that users want to engage with, through strong attention to detail, pushing boundaries with visuals and integrating modern frames of reference to convey the brand.

Through my experience, I have learnt the significance of user experience and user interface to guide the aesthetics of design, and the overall impact UX have on shaping a product.

I am passionate about user-centred design, and the impact it can have on people's lives. Above all else, I want to make a difference in the world, a real, quantifiable impact.

Oh, and I also like to code.

EXPERIENCE

Moneyfarm - May 2022 to Present Product Design Lead

Moneyfarm is known as one of the most innovative fintechs headquartered in the heart of London. The mission is to provide investment solutions and advice to protect and grow client wealth through time.

- Collaborating with and inspire product owners, engineers, marketing and the wider business, ensuring design helps drive the processes.
- Leading design in my own strategic team using this position to oversee the end-to-end product experience across two other teams.
- Mentoring and managing two product designers, sharing my design know-how and help them grow.
- Developing design strategies based on both insight and intuition and taking these forward hands-on to create industry leading solutions. Alongside this, strengthening the design capability and help maintain design as strategic and key to Moneyfarm's success.
- Create and validate insight-informed design solutions to meet customer and business goals.
- Delivering final UI design, concepts, flows and prototypes within an agile cross-functional environment.
- Lead Moneyfarm's design system and processes.
- Being the design facilitator and evangelist, building strong relationships in my team and beyond.
- Costa Coffee April 2021 to May 2022
 Senior Experience Designer
- cinch January 2020 to April 2021 Senior UX Designer
- TickX April 2019 to January 2020
 UX Lead
- TickX April 2018 to April 2019
 Senior UX Designer
- Talent Works International July 2017 to April 2018
 UX/UI Designer
- UK Point Of Sale October 2015 to July 2017
 Senior Web Designer
- MBi Group January 2015 to October 2015
 Senior Creative
- Elior December 2013 to January 2015
 Digital Designer
- McDonald's Restaurants Ltd (Head Office) June 2010 to December 2013 Graphic Web Designer
- Plus-Two January 2011, 1 day Graphic Designer (internship)
- X Artwork 1st July 2008 to 5th July 2008
 Graphic Designer (internship)
- **D21 Mediaworks -** May 2008 to July 2008 Graphic Designer (internship)

DESIGN SKILLS

Tools		Knowledge	
	Confluence	LIV/LII docigo	A/D tocting
Figma	Confluence	UX/UI design	A/B testing
Adobe XD	Jira Software	Wireframing	Workshops
Sketch	Slack	User-centered design	Web Accessibility
Adobe Target	Trello	Grid and layout	Data analytics
Adobe Photoshop	UserTesting	White space	UX research
Adobe Illustrator	Maze	Low/high prototyping	Design system
Miro	Useberry	Typography	Design Sprint
InVision	Hotjar	HTML/CSS	Mobile UX design
Zeplin	Google Analytics	Colour theory	Usability testing

RECOGNITION & FEATURED

Projects featured on Adobe Behance www.behance.net/simonhoang

Coding & Design Sprint articles featured on UX Collective - Medium online publishing https://simonhoang23.medium.com/

User Research article featured on The Startup - Medium online publishing https://simonhoang23.medium.com/

Usability Testing article featured on Bootcamp - Medium online publishing https://simonhoang23.medium.com/

Keynote Speaker at the UX Crunch event https://www.meetup.com/The-UX-Crunch-Manchester/events/259269010/

EDUCATION

- BA (Hons) Degree and Higher National Diploma 2006 to 2010
 Graphic Design University Of Salford
- BTEC National Diploma Graphic Design 2004 to 2006 City College Manchester
- BTEC National Diploma Fine Art (Partial) 2003 to 2004
 City College Manchester
- GNVQ Intermediate Art and Design 2002 to 2003
 Bury College
- 8 GCSE's 1997 to 2002 Plant Hill High School